Guide to the Printmaker File [1730]-2014, undated (bulk 1800-1860) PR 58
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: Prints 16 x 20" and smaller, 111472
  - Ehrgott, Forbriger & Co. (fl. 1860-1869), 177815 (Box E)
    - "B.F. Butler, Maj. Genl. U.S.A.", undated; 177854 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "S. R. Curtis, Major General U.S.A.", undated; 177857 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "Jefferson C. Davis, Brig. Genl U.S.A.", undated; 177840 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "E. Dumont, Brig. Genl. U.S.A.", undated; 177833 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "Commodore Foote, USN", undated; 177860 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "John C. Fremont. Maj. Genl. U.S.A.", undated; 177861 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "Wm. B. Franklin. Maj. Genl. U.S.A.", undated; 177867 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "Henry W. Halleck, Maj. Genl. U.S.A.", undated; 179097 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "Joe. Hooker, Maj. Genl. U.S.A.", undated; 179098 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "D.Hunter, Maj. Genl. U.S.A.", undated; 179099 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "A. McD. McCook, Brig. Genl. U.S.A.", undated; 179100 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "Robt. L. McCook, Col. 9th (First German) Regt. O. V. U.S.A.", undated; 179101 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "O. M. Mitchell, Brig. Genl. U.S.A.", undated; 179102 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "Commodore W. D. Porter, U.S. Navy", undated; 179103 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "W. S. Rosencrans. Maj. Genl. U.S.A", undated; 179104 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "W.H.L. Wallace, Brig. Genl. U.S.A.", undated; 179105 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
    - "John E. Wool. Maj. Genl. U.S.A.", undated; 179108 (Box "E", Folder unknown container)
  - Fabri, Ralph. (1894-1975), 20910
    - A Day in the Park (6/50), [1945]; 20911 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
      etching with drypoint
  - Falconer, John Mackie (1820-1903), 20904
    - The Earliest Art Centre in New York City, No. 180 Fulton St., AD 1816, et. seq." [The Parker Clover], 1880; 20909 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
      2 copies
    - First Methodist [Sanctuary] in New York City, 1880; 20908 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - [House Where Robert Fulton Served his Apprenticeship], 1893; 20907 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - 53 Maiden Lane [in]1842, Where Salmagundi was Published 1819" [J. Bucklass Tailor Shopfront], 1880; 20906 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - [North Dutch Church, Corner of William and Fulton], 1882; 20905 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
  - Farrer, Henry, 111787
    - "The Old Beach House Cor. Cedar & Greenwich, 1816; 111788 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - [On New York Bay], undated; 111789 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
  - Fernbach, Agnes B. (b. 1876), 20892
    - A Bit of the Harlem River, 1922; 20903 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
      printed by Ernest Roth
    - [Across Central Park Lake], 1929; 20902 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Across Central Park Lake, 1929; 20901 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - [Boat houses along Hudson River], 1920; 20900 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - [City Tree], 1932; 20899 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Cove, Central Park, undated; 20898 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Gregorian Door, Jumel Mansion, 1921; 20897 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Organ & Choir, Old Temple Emanu-El, N.Y., undated; 20896 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - [Soldiers' and Sailors' Monument], undated; 20895 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - [Tree at Riverside], undated; 20894 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - [Synagogue interior], undated; 20893 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
  - Fiene, Ernest (1894-1965), 20885
    - ['L' Train, baths, and barber shop](41/50), 1932; 20888 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
  - Flanagan, Albert (1886-1969), 20865
    - Afternoon Light, N.Y.C., 1930; 20884 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - The Church Missions House, New York: the World Headquarters of the Episcopal Church, 1932; 20883 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Coenties Slip, N.Y., 1931; 20882 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Dusk - William St., 1931; 20881 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - The Fountain. Central Park - N.Y., 1933; 20880 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Harbor Sunset, N.Y., 1934; 20879 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Jacob Street, N.Y., 1931; 20878 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Manhattan - The City of Towers, 1931; 20877 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Manhattan Shore - East River N.Y., 1930; 20876 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - 1931, 20875 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Morning Light, N.Y., 1934; 20874 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Night- New York, 1932; 20873 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Skyline-N.Y., 1933; 20872 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Storm at Sunset, 1932; 20871 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Towers of Manhattan - 42nd Street Group, 1930; 20870 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Towers of Manhattan - 57th Street Group, 1930; 20869 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Plaza Group - Towers of Manhattan, 1930; 20868 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Wall Street Group - Towers of Manhattan, 1931; 20867 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
    - Waterfront, New York, 1933; 20866 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
  - Flotten, Cy, 20863
    - Brooklyn Bridge, 1935; 20864 (Box "F", Folder unknown container)
  - Gayler, Julius F. (1872-1948), 20850
    - The Eternal Light New York, 1935; 20862 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
      aquatint
    - First Jewish Cemetery, 1934; 20861 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - Grace Church, 1938; 20860 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - "House of Lenox Mass 1936" [Winthrop House, designed by Gayler], 111673 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
      etching
    - MacDougal Alley, 1936; 20859 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - Municipal Center, 1937; 20858 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - New York Doorway [15 E. 81st], undated; 20857 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - New York Water Front [beginning of steel work for Empire State Building], 1930; 20856 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - New York Water Front, 1938; 20855 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - New York Water Front, 1939; 20854 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - [Old House Near East Haddam Connecticut], 1938; 111672 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - [Old Mill Western Massachusetts], 1935; 111671 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - "Peacock" [Grounds of Grenville L. Winthrop House, Lenox, Massachusetts], [1936]; 111674 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - Saint Paul's Church, New York (proof), 1938; 20853 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - Saint Paul's Church, New York (final take), 1938; 20852 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - Washington Square South, 1936; 20851 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
  - Glover, De Lay (ca. 1823-ca. 1863), 111663
    - "The Summer Dream", undated; 111669 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - "The Empty Cradle", undated; 111668 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - "The Evening Star", undated; 111667 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - [William Shakespeare], undated; 111666 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - [Oliver Goldsmith?], undated; 111665 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - [two untitled scenes, two untitled portraits, a printer's trade card, and two vignettes], undated; 111664 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
  - Grant, Gordon (1875-1962), 111661
    - "Fog Over Gloucester", undated; 111662 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
  - Gregory, Frank M. (1848-?), 20847
    - [Grace Church], undated; 20849 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
    - Twenty-Third St., Fifth Ave & Broadway, 1887; 20848 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
      etching on silk
  - Gross, Chaim (1904-1991), 111659
    - [Design to commemorate the 100th anniversary of laying the cornerstone of Central Synagogue in New York City], 1971; 111660 (Box "G", Folder unknown container)
      lithograph, impression 22 of 120
  - Hall, Charles B., 20844
    - Block House and Gate, Foot of Wall St., undated; 20846 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - Old House, corner Broad and Exchange Place, undated; 20845 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
  - Hanley, Frank, 20842
    - Jefferson Market Clock, undated; 20843 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
      block print
  - Haskell, Ernest (1876-1925), 111652
    - Birth announcement of Haskell's daughter Hildegarde, 1910; 111658 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - Greeting Card, undated; 111657 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - Holiday Card, undated; 111656 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - "In memorium" for Elizabeth Louise, Haskell's first wife, undated; 111655 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - Wedding announcement for Haskell's second marriage to Emma Loveland, 1920; 111654 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - Birth announcement for twins Ernest jr. and Josephine, 1921; 111653 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
  - Hassam, Childe (1859-1935), 20840
    - [New York Stock Exchange Floor], 1927; 20841 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
  - Henry, J., 111650
    - "Water Mill" [Nyack], 1880; 111651 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
  - Heriot, George (1766-1844), 111648
    - [Bordeaux, France], after 1816; 111649 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
  - Hewitt, Edward S. (1877-1962), 20835
    - Coal and Barges, undated; 20839 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - [East River Skyline], undated; 20838 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - [Midtown Towers, Waldorf Astoria], 1877; 20837 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - Tugs and Towers, undated; 20836 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
  - Hoff, Henry, 111628
    Includes "Views of New-York," 1850, color lithographs
    - "Astor Place Theatre", 111647 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "University" [Washington Square], 111646 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "Niblo's Hotel", 111645 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "Grace Church", 111644 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "Union-Square, Bird's Eye View", 111643 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "Stewart's Buildings and Broadway", 111642 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "New-York from Governor's Island", 111641 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "City Hall of Brooklyn", 111640 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
      after C. Autenrieth
    - "Castle Garden", 111639 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "Hospital of Brooklyn", 111638 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "Odd Fellows Hall", 111637 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "Croton Water Reservoir", 111636 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "City Hall", 111635 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "Tombs", 111634 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "Custom-House", 111633 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
      after C. Autenrieth, published by Hoff & Bloede
    - "Exchange", 111632 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "Institution for the Blind", 111631 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
    - "St. Paul's Church, Barnum's Museum and Astor House", 111630 (Box Hoff, Folder unknown container)
  - Hoover, Ellison (1888-1955), 20833
    - [Washington Square Arch in winter], [1920-1930]; 20834 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
  - Hoppe, F. Werner (active ca. 1920-1930), 20831
    - [Washington Square Arch], undated; 20832 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
  - Hunt, Leigh (1858-1959), 20828
    - Hell Gate Bridge, 1917; 20830 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - Washington Bridge, 1896; 20829 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
  - Hunter, F[rederick] Leo (1862-1943), 20822
    - Coenties Slip, South Street, 1881; 20827 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - [Equitable Building], unadted; 20826 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - [Grace Church], 1903; 20825 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - N.Y. Produce Exchange, 1887; 20824 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
    - The Old New York University Building, 1878; 20823 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
  - Jacobi, Eli (1898-1984), 20820
    - At Sharkey's, 1939; 20821 (Box "H", Folder unknown container)
      Linocut. Purchase, 1986. See also N-YHS collection of prints from the Works Progress Administration, Federal Arts Project (PR 345) for a Jacobi print.
  - Jones, Eugene Arthur (b. 1881), 20817
    - [Express Office, Fulton Market], undated; 20819 (Box "J", Folder unknown container)
    - [Pier 18- Fulton Market], undated; 20818 (Box "J", Folder unknown container)
  - Kangman, Edwin, 20815
    - Brooklyn Bridge, undated; 20816 (Box "K", Folder unknown container)
  - Kent, Rockwell, 114580
    - Starry Night, 1933; 114581 (Box K, Folder unknown container)
      Wood engraving. Source of Acquisition: Gift of Mr. & Mrs. Lawrence Appel, April 2016.
  - Kerr, Robert (1823-ca.1904), 111626
    - "The Customs House, Wall Street, Viewed from Broad Street", 1845; 111627 (Box "K", Folder unknown container)
      hand-colored lithograph after his own design, view No. 1 in "Views of New-York by Robert Kerr, architect"
  - King, L.H., 20813
    - The Little Church Around the Corner, 1897; 20814 (Box "K", Folder unknown container)
  - Kingman, Dong (1911-2000), 111624
    - "New Dawn, 1984 FAO World Food Day" (767/1000), 111625 (Box "K", Folder unknown container)
      General Note
      lithograph after watercolor (print and printed envelope)
  - Kohler, William (fl. 1830s-1840s)
    - [Ship labelled in gold as "Victoria"] sailing away full sail, bearing the Royal Standard and the Union Jack. The largest sail lifts as a flap to reveal portrait of Queen Victoria, bust length to right, wearing crown and ermine. Published by C. Tilt, Fleet Street., 1837 (Box F-L)
  - Koslow, Howard (b. 1924), 20811
    - The Bridge (36/100), 1983; 20812 (Box "K", Folder unknown container)
  - Landeck, Armin (1905-1984), 20809
    - Manhattan Nocturne, 1938; 20810 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
      drypoint
  - La Paglia, Anthony, 111616
    - "Seascape Series #3", [1930-1949]; 111623 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
      Colored woodblock print on mulberry paper. Impression 8 of 100.
    - "Landscape Series #2", [1930-1949]; 111622 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
      Colored woodblock print on mulberry paper. Impression 7 of 50.
    - "Landscape Series #3", [1930-1949]; 111621 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
      Colored woodblock print on mulberry paper. Impression 5 of 50.
    - [Snowscene], [1930-1949]; 111620 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
      Colored woodblock print on mulberry paper
    - [Still life], [1930-1949]; 111619 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
      Colored woodblock print on mulberry paper. Impression 21 of 37.
    - [Fish], [1930-1949]; 111618 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
    - [Birds], four different prints, [1930-1949]; 111617 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
  - Levine, Martin (b. 1945), 20807
    - 42nd & 5th, 1998; 20808 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
  - Lewis, Martin (1882-1962), 20805
    - Chance Meeting, 1940; 20806 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
      Drypoint etching
    - Boss of the Block, 1939; 114579 (Box L, Folder unknown container)
      Aquatint and etching, 11"x 15.5". Source of Acquisition: Gift of Mr. & Mrs. Lawrence Appel, April 2016.
  - Lowell, Nat (1880-1956), 20800
    - [Brooklyn Bridge and lower Manhattan from Brooklyn], 1931; 20804 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
    - Home of New York Chemical Mfg Co. 1824 [Tenth Ave.], undated; 20803 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
    - UN Headquarters, undated; 20802 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
    - [Washington Bridge, New York], 1931; 20801 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
  - Lubbers, Adriann (1892-1954), 79884
    - Brooklyn Bridge (55/68), 1929; 79885 (Box "L", Folder unknown container)
  - Marsh, Reginald (1898-1954), 114587
    - People's Follies, 1938; 114588 (Box "M")
      Etching. Source of Acquisition: Gift of Mr. & Mrs. Lawrence Appel, April 2016.
  - Meissner, Leo (1895-1977), 20797
    - Bleecker Street Follies (22/30), 1927; 20799 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
      linoleum cut
    - Journal Square, Jersey City (9/30), 1925; 20798 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
  - Meyerowitz, William (1887-1981), 20791
    - Grant's Tomb, 1919; 20796 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Modern New York, 1933; 20795 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - New York No. 1, or, 59th St. Bridge, 1931; 20794 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - On the Hudson, 1918; 20793 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Passing the Arch of Victory, 1919; 20792 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
  - Mielatz, Charles Frederick William (1864-1919), 20765
    - A Bit of Baxter Street, undated; 20790 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - [Aaron Burr's House, 11 Reade Street], 1898; 20789 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - [Astor House], 1910; 20788 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Catherine Market with Brooklyn Bridge, 1903; 20787 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Cherry Street, 1904; 20786 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Coenties Slip, 1907; 20785 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Colonnade Lafayette St. de Milhaus Home, 1907; 20784 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - The Dewey Arch, 1900; 20783 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - [Dutch Reformed Church], 1898; 20782 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Elevated Station at Night, undated; 20781 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Entrance to Brooklyn Bridge, 1892; 20780 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - In the Bowery, undated; 20779 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Jumel Mansion in Winter, 1911; 20778 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Lych Gate: Little Church around the Corner, [1902-1906]; 20777 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - No. 7 State Street, 1908; 20776 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Old Door on Houston Street, 1903; 20775 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Old Tom's on Thames Street, [1902-1906]; 20774 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Oyster Market, Foot of Christopher St., 1903; 20773 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Rainy Day Broadway, 1892; 20772 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Rainy Night, Madison Square, 1890; 20771 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Restaurant in Mott Street, 1906; 20770 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Seaman's Church Institute on State Street, 1909; 20769 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - [Wall Street, looking west to Trinity Church], undated; 20768 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - Washington Square, 1908; 20767 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
    - [Windmill], 1887; 20766 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
  - Milbert, Jacques Gerard (1766-1840). A Series of Picturesque Views in North America, Paris, 1825; 111584
    Lithographs.
    - "1st View of McComb's Mill's on the River Harlem near King's Bridge", 111613 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "2nd View of the River Harlem", 111612 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "Mr. McComb's House on the River Harlem near King's Bridge", 111611 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "McComb's Bridge Avenue", 111610 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "View of the Tavern on the Road to King's Bridge near Fort Washington", 111609 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "Front View the Fortifications at Harlem near [the city of] New-York", 111608 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "Mr. Van Den Heuvel's Country Seat", 111607 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "Spiten Devil's Creek", 111606 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "Bridge on the Croton 40 Miles N. of New-York", 111604 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "View of the Fall on Bronx River Lydich's Mill West Farms", 111603 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "View of Flushing (Long Island), North America. Oak-trees, under which George Fox, quaker, preached the Truths of the Gospel", 111602 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
    - "View of Flushing (Long Island), North America. Mr. Bowne's House. It remains in the possession of his family ever since 1661 time when it was built.", 111601 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      3 copies
    - "View of Lydick's Mill & House on Bronx River, West Farms", 111605 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
  - Milbert, Jacques Gerard (1766-1840).Itineraire pittoresque du fleuve Hudson et des Parties laterals, 1828-1829; 215652
    - "Interior of New-York, Provost Street and Chapel", 111599 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis Villeneuve, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 3
    - "Tarry-town where Major Andre was Captured", 111598 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis-Philippe-Alphonse Bichebois, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 4
    - "Sing-Sing or Mount Pleasant", 111597 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Leon Sabatier, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 5
    - "Haverstraw or Warren Landing", 111596 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis-Philippe-Alphonse Bichebois, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 6
    - "Lower Falls near the Residence of Mrs. Montgomery", 111595 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis Villeneuve, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 10
    - "Town of Hudson", 111594 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Leon Sabatier, Plate 11
    - "View of Hudson & the Catskill Mountains", 111593 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis-Philippe-Alphonse Bichebois, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 12
    - "Albany-Capital of the State of New-York", 111592 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Isidore-Laurent Deroy, Plate 13
    - "The Spot where General Burgoyne surrendered to General Gates", 111591 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Leon Sabatier, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 17
    - "General View of the Hudson at Adley's", 111590 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Louis-Julien Lacottet, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 29
    - "Falls on the Genesee Rivers", 111589 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Francois-Joseph Dupressoir, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 37
    - "Military Post. Sacketts Harbor", 111588 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Jean Louis Tirpenne, figures by Victor Adam, Plate 39
    - [Black River Near Lake Ontario], 111587 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Barnet & Doolitt, Plate 40 [ca. 1821-1822]
    - "Machine for the Portage on the Susquehanna", 111586 (Box Milbert, Jacques Gerard, Folder unknown container)
      lithography by Leon Sabatier, Plate 51
  - Mohn, Siguard M. (b. 1891), 20763
    - [St. Paul's Chapel, Broadway, N.Y.] (3/50), undated; 20764 (Box "M", Folder unknown container)
  - Moskowitz, Ira (1912-2001), 111582